Bhawna Kasliwal

2400 Chestnut Street, Apt 207 Philadelphia PA 19103 ~ (804) 248-7076 ~ bhawna.scorpio84@gmail.com

Personal Statement

I came to the US in February 2012 on a F-2 visa. The visa regulations governing the F-2 visa category do not permit me to work for wages or volunteer in a position that could be compensated. As a result, I have been restricted to performing only certain kinds of volunteer work.

Volunteer Experience

Assistant Chair for Fair Trade Philadelphia (FTPhl):

- During my tenure as Asst. Chair, FTPhl has made Philadelphia a Fair Trade City.
- Under my leadership, FTPhl has hosted a fair trade gift fair annually for the last 3 years.
- FTPhl has also hosted multiple fair trade walking tours & tabling events etc...

Committee Member with the Media Planning Committee:

- Represented Media at Fair Trade Federation Conference in Raleigh, NC (May '13), and the Chicago Fair Trade Conference (Oct' 2012).
- Contributed a presentation to the campaign to make Media plastic free.

Active member of the Mid-Atlantic Leadership Team for Fair Trade Campaign Help promote fair trade in towns, school and universities Acted as facilitator for the Campaign speaking about Sustainable Leadership

Graphic Design with Canva & Photoshop:

- Designed multiple marketing flyers for Fair Trade Philadelphia Committee & Media Fair Trade Committee.
- Creative Design: Designed campaign material for Sierra Club.

Volunteered at Tosheka Textiles in Philadelphia, PA.

Tosheka Textiles develops ways of reusing plastic waste in an ecologically friendly manner.

Sierra Club

- Volunteered with the Sierra Club at workshops for children at libraries and churches.
- Participated in various Sierra Club activities such as EPA hearings in Washington D.C., outreach programs at solar farms etc...

PAWS

Volunteered with the Philadelphia Animal Welfare Society (PAWS), a no-kill animal shelter

Work History

Mayoor School (School Teacher Aug 2010- May 2011)

• I was a class teacher for the Nursery and Lower Kindergarten level classes, I used to teach Hindi, English, Math, Rhymes, Personal Hygiene and Social Skills.

• I also observed and evaluated their performance, behavior and physical health, instructed students individually and in groups, helped students to adapt to different teaching methods to help them meet their varying needs and interests.

Shemrock Jingles Kindergarten School (Teacher April 2008-March 2010)

• Kindergarten teacher

Tara Projects, New Delhi, India (June 2007 - June 2008)

- Tara Projects is one of the largest fair-trade manufacturers of jewelry, bags, and soap-stone, metal, wood, glass, lac, zari, horn, and bone products in India.
- I was involved in product development, design phase, sample co-ordination, and quality assurance.

Rangsutra Crafts, New Delhi, India (Aug 2005-May 2007)

- Rangsutra Crafts represents a thousand artisans in Rajasthan and Uttranchal by forming a bridge between consumers and the artisans.
- My role was to determine the marketing strategy changes by reviewing operating and financial statements and departmental sales records.
- My profile also included Product management, including ordering, receiving, price changes, handling damaged products, and returns.

Languages Known

• Hindi & English

Education

- University of Delhi, *Bachelor of Vocational Studies* (2002-2005)
- Jewelry Design, International Polytechnic for Women (2007)

Refrences

Elizabeth Killough Yoko Barnes Renee Bowers